Chris Ryan Designer / Developer

416-433-7988 chris@ryandesigns.ca ryandesigns.ca linkedin.com/in/ryandesigns9

With over two decades of expertise in design and web development, my enthusiasm for creativity fuels my work across various fields. My goal is to create pieces that are not only visually appealing but also provide a flawless user experience. I specialize in responsive design, theme development and creating extensive bots for platforms like Discord, Telegram and X. I am always committed to staying at the forefront of my field, continuously exploring new technologies, trends and techniques to add to my skillset.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Video/Design:

- 20+ years of Adobe Creative Suite experience
- Well versed in both mobile & web UI/UX design. (Primarily using Figma)
- Extensive Adobe Premiere and After Effects editing work
- Stream production and design (OBS, vMix, TikTok Live Studio)

Development:

- Well versed in various coding languages (HTML, CSS, JS, SwiftUI, Python, SQL, PHP)
- Extensive web framework experience (Flask, Next.JS, React, Bootstrap, Tailwind, etc)
- Ecommerce development using different platforms (Shopify, Wordpress, Magento)
- Discord / Telegram bot development with customization & MongoDB integrations
- Various uses of public and private APIs along with AI / ML integrations.
- Smart Contract development using Solidity
- Web3 Python bot experience (discord, telegram, project art generation, automation)
- iOS Mobile App Development using Swift
- Unity experience building out worlds to be used in VR games.
- Unreal Engine experience building out worlds to be used in Fortnite Creative.

Testing:

- Jira & DevTrack to track and manage reported issues, bugs discovered during testing
- Selenium and Unity Test Framework to execute comprehensive black box testing
- Perforce to manage and track version changes through development
- Unity Test Framework to test games and bugs during development.
- Wireshark to monitor network traffic and ensuring api calls are correctly being made



WORK EXPERIENCE

Founder & Designer / Developer

RyanDesigns.ca | 05/2015 - Current

- Established and operated a successful graphic design and web development company
- Created and maintained websites for clients utilizing modern web frameworks such as Bootstrap, ReactJS, Wordpress, Shopify, etc.
- Designed and developed branding materials, including logos, marketing collateral, and print materials
- Managed multiple projects simultaneously while meeting deadlines and maintaining high-quality standards (400+ 5 Star Freelancer reviews)

QA Tester

Electronic Arts Canada | 03/2013 - 05/2015

- Found and reported issues, bugs, and inconsistencies through ad hoc testing
- Monitored and reported black box coverage in assigned areas, tracking issues from beginning to end
- Clarified issues as they arose and communicated test plans to leadership
- Created testing briefs based on feature and technical briefs of each owned feature
- Drove the creation and execution of test plans in partnership with development and production teams

























PROJECTS

RinkRivals.com

Developed an online platform league with stat tracking website from the ground up. A discord full of various bot commands & an interactive stream for viewers to watch three times a week.

SportsLights for Philips Hue

Developed an iPhone app that syncs with your Philips Hue lights and triggers based on live sports events.

Sportshex.com

Website dedicated to sports enthusiasts, providing a resource for hex codes for various teams and leagues

FNCreativeDB.xyz

Created a database and user-friendly website for Fortnite Creative mode, showcasing community-generated content & maps

Sportsgamer.GG

Helped with an online platform for sports gaming enthusiasts, featuring news, reviews, and events related to sports video games.

Full portfolio at: ryandesigns.ca



EDUCATION

Advertising -**Ontario College Diploma**

2006-2008 - Durham College (Oshawa, ON)